Guide to the Alan Pryce-Jones Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1876-1996; Series I; 11.5; (28 boxes)
  - ALAN PRYCE-JONES CORRESPONDENCE
    - Wooster, Mary ("Mitzi"), 1942-68, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1315-1316)
      Letter of 1944 Nov 22 contains
      note from Thérèse Pryce-Jones
    - World Opinion, 1947 Nov 5 (Box 25, Folder 1317)
    - Worth, Irene, 1958 Apr 1 (Box 25, Folder 1318)
    - Wyndham, Ursula, 1988 Aug 26 (Box 25, Folder 1319)
    - Wynne-Tyson, Jon, 1986 Dec 23 (Box 25, Folder 1320)
    - "Y" general, 1963-94, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1321)
    - The Yale Review, 1992 Nov 29 (Box 25, Folder 1322)
    - Yale University Library
      See: Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Box 2, folder 86
    - Young, Gavin, 1963-88, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1323)
    - Young, G. M., 1951, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1324)
    - Younghusband, Francis Edward, Sir, 1928 Aug 21 (Box 25, Folder 1325)
    - "Z" general, 1949, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 1326)
    - Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1953-59 (Box 25, Folder 1327)
    - Zaehner, R. C., 1953 Dec 9 (Box 25, Folder 1328)
    - Zangwill, O. L., 1954 Aug 31 (Box 25, Folder 1329)
    - Empty envelopes, 1928-92, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1330)
    - Unidentified correspondents
      - Incomplete (missing signatures), 1930-89, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1331)
      - Illegible signatures, 1931-85, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1332)
      - Unsigned, 1938-80, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1333)
      - "Tante Anna", 1936 (Box 26, Folder 1334)
      - ----, Anne, 1957-58 (Box 26, Folder 1335)
      - ----, Gordon, 1946-49 (Box 26, Folder 1336)
      - ----, Harold, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1337)
      - ----, Katharine, 1991-94 (Box 26, Folder 1338)
      - ----, Mary, 1995, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1339)
      - ----, Philippa, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1340)
      - ----, Robert, 1994-95 (Box 26, Folder 1341)
      - ----, "Tommy", 1932 (Box 26, Folder 1342)
      - General first names "A", 1940-87, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1343)
      - General first names "B", 1931-88, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1344)
      - General first names "C", 1942-89, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1345)
      - General first names "D", 1958-66, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1346)
      - General first names "E-F", 1936-90, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1347)
      - General first names "G", 1958-65, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1348)
      - General first names "H", 1945-94, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1349)
      - General first names "I", 1966, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1350)
      - General first names "J", 1954-95, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1351)
      - General first names "K", 1960-63, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1352)
      - General first names "L", 1952-73, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1353)
      - General first names "M", 1957-72, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1354)
      - General first names "N", n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1355)
      - General first names "P", 1955-89, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1356)
      - General first names "R", 1963-70, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1357)
      - General first names "S", 1937-92, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1358)
      - General first names "T-Y", 1993, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1359)
    - Blank greeting cards and stationery, 1958, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1360)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - To and from Louisa Jane McDonnell, Countess of Antrim
      - Broch, Elisa, 1921 Jul 21 (Box 26, Folder 1361)
      - Milner, Alfred Milner, Viscount, 1920 Nov 9 (Box 26, Folder 1362)
      - To unidentified recipient, 1906 (Box 26, Folder 1363)
        "Extract from Mr. Patterson
        of [Fomitos?]' letter to Molly"
    - To Mary, Duchess of Buccleuch and Queensberry
      - Armstrong, Nancy J., 1978 Jun 11 (Box 26, Folder 1364)
      - Coward, Noël, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1365)
      - Fairbanks, Mary Lee, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1366)
      - Harrod, Wilhelmine Margaret Eve Cresswell, Lady ("Billa"), 1980-85, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1367)
      - Leslie, Anita, 1983 Jun 7 (Box 26, Folder 1368)
      - Lindsay, Loelia (Duchess of Westminster) (Box 26, Folder 1369)
      - [Massigli?], Odette, 1986 Mar 1, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1370)
      - Murray, John ("Jock"), 1973 Apr 10 (Box 26, Folder 1371)
      - Olga, Princess of Yugoslavia, 1984 Oct 8 (Box 26, Folder 1372)
      - Origo, Iris, 1976 Aug 3 (Box 26, Folder 1373)
      - Scott, David (David John Montagu- Douglas-Scott, Sir), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1374)
      - Unidentified, 1980, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1375)
    - To Lady Victoria Dawnay
      - [Bikanir, Maharaja of?] ("Louise"), 1916 Nov 25 (Box 26, Folder 1376)
      - Dane, Louis, Sir, 1908 Mar 27 (Box 26, Folder 1377)
      - Grey, Albert Henry George Grey, 4th Earl, 1876 (Box 26, Folder 1378)
      - St. Albans, Osborne de Vere Beauclerk, Duke of, 1918 Jul 20 (Box 26, Folder 1379)
      - White, George Stuart, Sir, 1908 Jan 5 (Box 26, Folder 1380)
    - To and from George Dix
      - Durlacher Bros. (George Dix) to Frank Duncan, 1967 Jun 1 (Box 26, Folder 1381)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1992, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 1382)
    - To Larry Hudson
      - Pryce-Jones, Adam, 1994 Nov 24 (Box 26, Folder 1383)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1981-90 (Box 26, Folder 1384)
    - To Mary Jean Kempner
      - Bate, Zara, Dame, 1970 Apr 2 (Box 26, Folder 1385)
      - Christiansen, O., 1969 Sep 8 (Box 26, Folder 1386)
    - To Mary Loder
      - Mercer, Doris Gibbins, 1966 Feb 2 (Box 27, Folder 1387)
      - Pryce-Jones, Adrian, 1957-68, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1388)
      - Pryce-Jones, Vere Dawnay, 1953 Jan 3 (Box 27, Folder 1389)
    - To Mary Caroline Grey Elliot-Murray- Kynynmound, Countess of Minto
      - Buchan, John, 1927 Feb 16 (Box 27, Folder 1390)
      - Kitchener, Horatio Herbert Kitchener, Earl, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1391)
    - To Stanley Morison
      - Greene, Graham, 1947 Nov 6 (Box 27, Folder 1392)
      - Morgan, Charles, 1948 Feb 6 (Box 27, Folder 1393)
      - William Heinemann Ltd., 1947 Mar 19 (Box 27, Folder 1394)
    - To Hélène Propper de Callejon
      - Heine-Geldern, Alice, 1935-47 (Box 27, Folder 1395)
      - Wooster, Mary ("Mitzi"), 1975 Aug 22 (Box 27, Folder 1396)
    - To and from Adrian Pryce-Jones
      - Mercer, Doris Gibbins, 1964 Jul 13 (Box 27, Folder 1397)
      - Pryce-Jones, Syra, Lady, 1963 Mar 6 (Box 27, Folder 1398)
    - To David and Clarissa Pryce-Jones
      - Leach, Colin (photocopy), 1987 Jan 9 (Box 27, Folder 1399)
      - Mercer, Doris Gibbins, 1960 Dec 27 (Box 27, Folder 1400)
      - "Tante [Bébé?]", 1963 (Box 27, Folder 1401)
    - To Henry Morris Pryce-Jones
      - Conway, William Martin, Sir, 1925 Sep 17 (Box 27, Folder 1402)
      - Dawson, Geoffrey, 1925 Jul 28 (Box 27, Folder 1403)
      - Elizabeth II, Queen of Great Britain, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 1404)
        Written by secretaries on the
        (then) Princess's behalf
        accompanied by photographs
        of wedding gifts to her from
        the Royal household
      - Great Britain. Army, Coldstream Guards, 1939 Mar 28 (Box 27, Folder 1405)
      - Great Britain. Army, Honourable Corps of Gentlemen at Arms, 1922 Dec 20 (Box 27, Folder 1406)
      - [Gross?], C. W., 1926 Oct 4 (Box 27, Folder 1407)
        Encloses letter from Sir Owen
        Seaman to Patrick Chalmers
      - John, William Goscombe, Sir, 1920, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1408)
      - Luxmoore, H. E., 1924 Sep 22 (Box 27, Folder 1409)
      - Magdalen College, Oxford University, 1927 (Box 27, Folder 1410)
      - Montagu-Douglas-Scott, Francis George, 1938 (Box 27, Folder 1411)
      - Pryce-Jones, Vere Dawnay, 1914 Nov 18 (Box 27, Folder 1412)
      - Ramsay, A. B. (Alan Beville), 1924 Feb 18 (Box 27, Folder 1413)
      - The Spectator, 1924 Sep 2 (Box 27, Folder 1414)
      - Vaughan, E. L., 1924-26, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1415)
      - Whitworth, Aymer W.
        See: Series IV, Personal Papers, Eton College reports, Box 61, folder 2321-2325
      - Other correspondence, 1908-52 (Box 27, Folder 1416)
    - To Sir Pryce Pryce-Jones
      - Balfour, Arthur James Balfour, Earl of, 1888 (Box 27, Folder 1417)
      - Churchill, Randolph Henry Spencer, Lord, 1890 Feb 14 (Box 27, Folder 1418)
    - To and from Thérèse Pryce-Jones
      - Colefax, Sibyl, Lady, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1419)
      - Grenier, Jean, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1420)
      - Hinks, R. P., 1938 Mar 11 (Box 27, Folder 1421)
      - Horner, David, 1950 Feb 8 (Box 27, Folder 1422)
      - Pryce-Jones, Adrian, [ca. 1940] (Box 27, Folder 1423)
      - Pryce-Jones, Vere Dawnay, 1938-49, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1424)
      - To "Nana", 1934 Sep 14 (Box 27, Folder 1425)
        Accompanied by two photographs
        of David Pryce-Jones as a child,
        one of them dated 1939
      - Other correspondence, 1934-49, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1426)
    - To and from Vere Dawnay Pryce-Jones
      - Betjeman, John, Sir, 1927 Jan 21 (Box 27, Folder 1427)
      - Buckmaster, Maurice J., 1935 Dec 24 (Box 27, Folder 1428)
      - Dawnay, Adelaide, 1923 Dec 24 (Box 27, Folder 1429)
        Encloses letter from Laurence
        Binyon to Adelaide Dawnay
      - Horner, David, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 1430)
      - [Jameson?], n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1431)
      - Lander, John, 1920-28 (Box 27, Folder 1432)
      - Luxmoore, H. E., 1925 (Box 27, Folder 1433)
      - Ponsonby, Frederick Edward Grey, Sir, 1923-31 (Box 27, Folder 1434)
      - Pryce-Jones, Eleanor Morris, 1905 May 4 (Box 27, Folder 1435)
      - Shaw, R. J. H., n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1436)
      - [Triens?], J. M., 1927 (Box 27, Folder 1437)
      - Wooster, Mary ("Mitzi"), 1935 Aug 15 (Box 27, Folder 1438)
      - Other correspondence, 19[05]-62 (Box 27, Folder 1439)
    - To Sir John Collings Squire
      - Beerbohm, Max, Sir, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1440)
      - Davies, W. H., 1930 Sep 16 (Box 27, Folder 1441)
      - De la Mare, Walter, 1931 Jun 23 (Box 27, Folder 1442)
      - Douglas, Alfred Bruce, Lord, 1929 Jun 12 (Box 27, Folder 1443)
      - George S. Harrap and Company, 1930 Oct 21 (Box 27, Folder 1444)
      - Graves, Robert, 1930 Sep 16, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1445)
      - Lubbock, Percy, 1929 Aug 12 (Box 27, Folder 1446)
      - Nichols, Robert Malise Bowyer, 1931 Apr 23, n.d. (Box 27, Folder 1447)
      - Strachey, Lytton, 1929 Aug 13 (Box 27, Folder 1448)
      - Shaw, Bernard, 1929 Sep 17 (Box 27, Folder 1449)
      - Sassoon, Siegfried, 1929 Feb 12 (Box 27, Folder 1450)
      - "M. B.", 1931 Jun 8 (Box 27, Folder 1451)
    - To Mary Wooster ("Mitzi")
      - Great Britain. Trading with the Enemy Department, 1947-56 (Box 27, Folder 1452)
      - Westminster Bank Limited, 1946 Jan 17 (Box 27, Folder 1453)
      - Other correspondence, 1949-81 (Box 27, Folder 1454)
    - Other Third Party Correspondence
      - Athlone, Alexander George Cambridge of Teck, Earl of, to George Charles Bingham, Earl of Lucan, 1938 May 23 (Box 28, Folder 1455)
      - Berlin, Isaiah, to Hamish Hamilton, 1956 Nov 3 (Box 28, Folder 1456)
      - Blackwood, James H., to Evan Morgan (Viscount Tredegar), 1927 Mar 28 (Box 28, Folder 1457)
      - Boardman, Fon W. (Oxford University Press), to Richard Kluger, 1963 Dec 13 (Box 28, Folder 1458)
      - Cutmore, Mildred, to Archduchess Rosemary of Austria, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1459)
      - [Derby, Lord?] to "Malcolm", [1951] (Box 28, Folder 1460)
      - Dewsbery, Stewart, to The Observer, 1942 Nov 9 (Box 28, Folder 1461)
      - Dow, Mary F., to Ada Elizabeth Chesterton, 1941 Jul 6 (Box 28, Folder 1462)
        Carbon copy
      - Garvin, James L., to Richard James Herbert Shaw, 1927 Apr 5 (Box 28, Folder 1463)
      - Gascoigne, A. D. E. ("Joe"), to Lt. Col. Patrick Barclay, 1941 (Box 28, Folder 1464)
      - Gerhard, William, to Anthony Powell, 1952 Oct 1 (Box 28, Folder 1465)
      - Graham, W. S., to "Marie", 1958 Jun 3 (Box 28, Folder 1466)
      - Lloyd's Bank to Daniel K. Thorne, 1975 Jun 3 (Box 28, Folder 1467)
      - Mackait, Margaret, to "Dickie", 1932 May 16 (Box 28, Folder 1468)
      - Meiklejohn, Roderick, to [Lirriela?], 1930 Oct 14 (Box 28, Folder 1469)
      - Nicolson, Nigel, to "Robin", 1968 May 9 (Box 28, Folder 1470)
      - O'Hara, Constance, to Anne Freemantle, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1471)
      - Propper de Callejon, Eduardo, to Monsieur [A. D. E.?] Gascoigne, 1945 Feb 20 (Box 28, Folder 1472)
      - Scharf, Olive, to "Dick", 1945 Jul 25 (Box 28, Folder 1473)
      - Sitwell, Osbert, to Malcolm Bullock, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1474)
      - Thomas, Robin, to "Mickey", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1475)
      - Tomlinson, Kathleen, to "Maurice", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1476)
      - Vreeland, Diana, to Mrs. Persifor Fraser ("Peggy"), 1987 Nov 9 (Box 28, Folder 1477)
      - [Watson?], Colin, to Hamish Hamilton, 1981 Jan 29 (Box 28, Folder 1478)
      - Williams, Jane, to Senator and Mrs. Jacob Javits (photocopy), 1974 Sep 11 (Box 28, Folder 1479)
      - "Aspasia" to Mr. Bower, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1480)
      - "Maurice" to "[Charles?]", 1938 Jun 18 (Box 28, Folder 1481)
      - "Sheila" to Roger de Candolle (Box 28, Folder 1482)
      - Unidentified to "Alix", n.d. (Box 28, Folder 1483)
- Writings, [ca.1914]-96; Series II; 6.5; (16 boxes)
  Series II, Writings, is organized
  into twelve subseries: Books; Short
  Stories; Essays, Lectures and Radio
  Appearances; Reviews; Obituaries,
  Eulogies, and Tribute Speeches
  Lyrics, Libretti, and Plays; Poetry
  Juvenilia; Translations and Edited Works
  Scrapbooks; Notebooks; and Writings
  of Others. The arrangement of each
  is noted at the head of the subseries
  or under subheadings where appropriate.
  - BOOKS
    Arranged alphabetically by title
    under each heading
    - Fiction
      - People in the South
        - Holograph manuscript, bound volume, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 1484)
        - Dust jacket for American edition, Hot Places, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 1485)
        - Reviews, 1932 (Box 29, Folder 1486)
      - Pink Danube
        - Holograph manuscript, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 1487)
        - Related materials, 1939, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 1488)
          Includes a letter from Field
          Roscoe & Co. about possible
          libel suits, a letter from
          "Derek" to Liliane de
          Rothschild about the identity
          of the author, and a royalty
          statement
      - Seven Against Thebes
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, [1935?] (Box 29, Folder 1489-1492)
        - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1935?] (Box 30, Folder 1493-1496)
      - Untitled Novel
        - Option agreement with Houghton Mifflin Company, unsigned, 1957 Apr 26 (Box 30, Folder 1497)
    - Non-Fiction
      - "Axel Springer"
        - Contract with Andre Deutsch Limited, 1969 Aug 15 (Box 30, Folder 1498)
        - Research materials, 1963-69 (Box 30, Folder 1499)
      - Beethoven
        - Holograph manuscript, 1932 (Box 30, Folder 1500)
        - Reviews, 1933-58 (Box 30, Folder 1501)
        - Contract with Reader's Digest for additional text, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 1502)
      - The Bonus of Laughter
        - Holograph manuscript, 1979-[86] (Box 30, Folder 1503-1505)
        - Reviews, 1987-88 (Box 30, Folder 1506)
      - "Intellectuals at Sea"
        - Contract with and advance check from The Beacon Press, 1950 Oct 19 (Box 30, Folder 1507)
      - Private Opinion: A Commonplace Book
        - Holograph manuscript, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 1508)
        - Reviews, 1936 (Box 31, Folder 1509)
      - "Prose Literature 1945-1950"
        - Contract with the British Council, 1951 Sep 28 (Box 31, Folder 1510)
      - The Spring Journey
        - Holograph manuscript, 1931 (Box 31, Folder 1511)
        - Reviews, 1931-36 (Box 31, Folder 1512)
      - "The Story of the Hapsburgs"
        - Contracts with Chatto & Windus and Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1959 (Box 31, Folder 1513)
  - SHORT STORIES
    Arranged alphabetically with
    the exception of notebook at
    end of group
    - "American Comedy," draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1514)
    - "Christmas Disaster," galley proofs, n.d.
    - "The Country House," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1515)
    - "The Country Palace," holograph draft, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1516)
    - "Ecuador I," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1517)
    - "An Evening" ("The Tulips")
      Holograph draft
      See: Essays, notebook, Box 35, folder 1690
      - Draft fragment, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1518)
      - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1519)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1520)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1521)
    - "Fantasia," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1522)
    - "Gringos," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1523)
    - "A House in the Country," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1524)
      Accompanied by letter of
      transmittal to Jock Murray,
      for The Cornhill, and
      photocopy of same corrected
      typescript
    - "Imaginary Conversation," draft, typescript, corrected (Box 31, Folder 1525)
    - "The Letters of Lord Albatross," holograph draft, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1526)
    - "Letters From Paris," draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1527)
    - "Lye House," holograph draft, n.d. (Box 31, Folder 1528)
    - "Miss Betty"
      - Holograph draft, 1936 (Box 32, Folder 1529)
      - Printed version, 1938 (Box 32, Folder 1530)
    - "Miss Tremlow," draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1531)
    - "Mrs. Slaney's Conversion"
      See also: notebook, Box 32, folder 1549
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1532)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1533)
    - "Novels Unwritten: III, The Artist in Defeat," draft, typescript, corrected (Box 32, Folder 1534)
    - "The Paris House," draft, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 32, Folder 1535)
      See also: notebook Box 32, folder 1549
    - "A Passage at the Court of Tartary," holograph draft, 1928 (Box 32, Folder 1536)
    - "Passage Through These Looms"
      - "Mrs. Eagle," holograph draft, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1537)
      - "Mrs. Eagle," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1538)
      - "Mrs. Eagle," drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1539-1540)
      - "Passage Through These Looms, II. Peter Ferrard," empty file folder, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1541)
    - People in the South
      See: Books, Box 29, folder 1484
    - "The Red Hot Heart," draft, typescript, corrected, 1930 (Box 32, Folder 1542)
      transmittal to unidentified
      publisher
    - "Saturday to Monday"
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1543)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1544)
    - "Scraps Found in a Can"
      - Draft, typescript, setting copy, [1930] (Box 32, Folder 1545)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1930] (Box 32, Folder 1546)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1547)
    - "Seven Deadly Sins: Integrity," draft, typescript, corrected (Box 32, Folder 1548)
    - Holograph drafts in bound volume (Box 32, Folder 1549)
      Contains:
      "Doing Good"
      "Inheritance"
      "Samson in Gaza"
      "Saturday to Monday"
      "The Paris House"
      "Mrs Slaney's Conversion"
    - Untitled Drafts and Fragments
      - "She thought about him a great deal [...]"
        - Holograph draft, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1550)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1977 Dec 4 (Box 32, Folder 1551)
        - Draft, photocopy of corrected typescript, 1977 Dec 4 (Box 32, Folder 1552)
      - Story in four parts, "Sunday jumped [...]," draft, typescript carbon and typescript (Box 32, Folder 1553-1554)
      - Fragment, "The chair was a red leather chair [...]," holograph, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1555)
      - Fragment, "I read in the paper [...]," holograph, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1556)
      - Fragment, "Miss Percival bicycled slowly [...]," holograph, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1557)
      - Fragment, "Once a long-legged [...]," holograph, n.d. (Box 32, Folder 1558)
  - ESSAYS, LECTURES, AND RADIO APPEARANCES
    the exception of notebooks
    filed at the end of the group
    - "The 1549 Prayer Book," proof, Times Literary Supplement, 1949 Mar 12
      See also: Reviews, Notebook, Box 38, folder 1785
    - "After the Absurd What?", printed version, Poiesis: the Magazine of the Festival of Creative Arts, 1964 Oct 10 (Box 33, Folder 1559)
    - "Alan Pryce-Jones in Russia," printed version, The Listener, 1972 Jan 13 (Box 33, Folder 1560)
    - "Alan Pryce-Jones Interview," transcript, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1561)
    - "Alan Pryce-Jones leaving for America looks back at England," galley proof, The Listener
    - "Alan Pryce Jones Takes a Sharp Look at the Foundations," typescript photocopy and printed, The Listener, 1974 May 23 (Box 33, Folder 1562)
    - "Alan Pryce-Jones's Texas," BBC broadcast script, typescript mimeograph and printed, The Listener, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 1563)
    - "An Ambassador of Peace" [Lord D'Abernon], drafts, typescript, corrected, and typescript carbon, [1948] (Box 33, Folder 1564)
    - The American Imagination (anthology), review of APJ's introduction to, [1960] (Box 33, Folder 1565)
    - "The American Migraine," galley proofs, The Listener, n.d.
    - "Andean Diary"
      See: Series IV, Diaries, Box 48, Folder 2093
    - "Anonymity," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1566)
    - "Arrival in Bolivia," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, [1932] (Box 33, Folder 1567)
      Accompanied by letters to The Listener in response
    - "The Art of Vladimir Nabokov," draft, typescript carbon, corrected, and printed, Harper's Magazine (Box 33, Folder 1568)
    - "Aspectos de la Soledad Britanica," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1569)
    - "Aspects de la Solitude Britannique," draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1570)
    - "Atatürk's Heirs: Proud and Sensitive People Looks at Britain," printed version, The Times (Box 33, Folder 1571)
    - "B'ware Eight on Nine Point," galley proof, Times Literary Supplement, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1572)
    - "The Case for Prose: The Evolution of Wit-writing"
      - Draft, typescript carbon, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1573)
      - Script for BBC broadcast, typescript mimeograph, 1947 Nov 20 (Box 33, Folder 1574)
        Autographed by Ronald Simpson
    - "Collecting: a Magnificent Obsession"
      See: Series I, Correspondence, Sotheby's, Inc., Box 23, Folder 1133
    - "Coming Home on Leave" ("Broadcast to Ecuador"), draft, typescript carbon, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 1575)
    - Concise Encyclopedia of World Literature 1900 to Today, contract for two articles, 1959 Sep 1 (Box 33, Folder 1576)
    - "The Creative Spirit of the 1920s"
      See: notebook, Box 35, folder 1689
    - "La crise du livre contemporain anglais," lecture
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1577)
      - Partial draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1578)
    - "Discussion on Techinque of Translation," transcript of conversation between Ilsa Barea & APJ, 1952 Jan 8 (Box 33, Folder 1579)
    - "Do Conventions Matter?", printed version, The Listener, 1941 Dec 18 (Box 33, Folder 1580)
      "Part of a discussion between
      John Mabbot, Elizabeth Bowen,
      Lt.-Commander J. Noad, and Capt.
      Alan Pryce-Jones"
    - "Do Males Dress to Attract Females? Or to Annoy their Elders? or to Band?", proof, Mademoiselle, 1966 Feb
    - "Donizetti," printed version, Milo, 1929 (Box 33, Folder 1581)
    - "England," printed version, Saturday Review, 1961 Jul 29 (Box 33, Folder 1582)
    - "English Writing: The Novel Today and Yesterday," script for BBC broadcast, typescript mimeograph, 1959 Aug 7 (Box 33, Folder 1583)
    - "An Englishman looks at Modern American Literature," lecture
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1584)
      - Draft, typescript, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1585)
      - Draft, typescript carbon, n.d. (Box 33, Folder 1586)